Mengniang.
مينج نيانغ
Are you okay?
هل أنت بخير؟
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
There are
‫هنا كلها
so many dead poisonous insects.
الكثير من الحشرات السامة الموتى
Xiao?
اضحك
Is it Yixiao Hall?
هل يمكن أن يكون الضحك
Yixiao Hall?
‫ابتسامة‬
Isn't it Uncle San's...
‫هذا ليس العم الثالث
Search this room carefully.
‫ابحثوا بعناية في هذه الغرفة‬
Open it.
افتح.
Yes. Yes.
حاضر حاضر
Five hundred grams of Four-Soul Grass.
عشرة تايل من عشب الأرواح
One hundred grams of Scorpion Grass.
اثنان ليانغ من العطر
Add them to the soup
ويصنع الحساء
and feed the poisonous insects with the soup.
استخدم الحساء لإطعام الحشرات السامة
Then this poison is formed.
هذا السم
The incense is the trigger of the efficacy
لإغراء البخور
and the antidote at the same time.
‫لإزالة العطر‬
What are these?
ما هذا؟
I read this
لقد رأيت
in a poison-making book.
قرأته في كتاب إنتاج المخدرات
This is a prescription for poison production.
هذه وصفة إنتاج المخدرات
Poison production?
إنتاج المخدرات
What poison?
أي نوع من السم
The poison that makes you demonic.
السم الذي يجعلكِ مجنونة
Besides,
علاوة على ذلك
these prescriptions are listed according to their toxicity;
الوصفة في الداخل
the later,
كلما تراجعت
the more poisonous.
كلما كانت فعالية الدواء أقوى
Keep searching.
استمر في البحث
Hai Liyuan.
نهر البحر
Master, here's a door.
يا صاحب الدار هناك باب
Master.
يا صاحب الدار
Hit harder!
اضربوه بقوة
Young Master, what should we do?
!يا سيدي، ماذا نفعل؟
Fight against them!
هيا بنا
Where does this lead to?
‫إلى أين يؤدي هذا‬
Everyone, this way.
من هنا
Mengniang.
مينج نيانغ
Xixi, hurry!
شي شي، بسرعة
Jin Gang!
جين قانغ جين
Young Master!
سيدي
You leave now.
اذهبوا بسرعة
I'll handle this.
سأحملها هنا
Being able to serve you
يمكنني خدمتك
is the happiest thing in my life.
هو أسعد شيء في حياتي
Take care of Mengniang for me.
ساعدني في رعاية مينج نيانغ
I'm not leaving. I'll accompany you.
لن أرحل، سأرافقك
Jin Gang.
جين قانغ
Open it. Let's go together.
افتحه لنذهب معا
Didn't you teach me to see in a big picture?
ألم تعلمني من قبل أن أركز على الوضع العام
I'm doing what you taught me now.
أنا الآن أركز على الوضع العام
Leave now.
اذهب بسرعة
Hurry.
هيا بنا
Step aside.
‫انهض‬
Bai Ran.
‫باي يان‬
Is this the secret room of Hai Liyuan?
هل هذه غرفة سرية من حوض البحر؟
Where are the others?
أين الآخرون؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف
One more time.
‫سأسألك مرة أخرى‬
Where are the others?
أين الآخرون؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف
Don't come over.
‫لا تقترب مني‬
Don't move!
لا تتحرك
You two, take him back
خذوه إلى المنزل
and ask someone to move all the things here away.
‫اطلب من الناس نقل كل الأشياء هنا‬
The rest of you
‫الآخرون‬
follow me.
اتبعوني
Yes.
حاضر
A bunch of losers!
مجموعة من النفايات
Go after them!
الحقوا بهم
Yes. Yes.
حاضر حاضر
Stop!
قف
Your method is working.
طريقتك تعمل
Great. We can go back to the corridor.
رائع يمكننا العودة إلى الممر
Back to the corridor?
نعود إلى الممر
They will investigate this forest thoroughly.
سيبحثون في هذه الغابة بكل تأكيد
With our current situation,
بناء على وضعنا الحالي
we can't go far.
لا يمكننا الركض بعيداً
The corridor is the safest now.
على العكس الطريق الآمن الآن
Master.
يا صاحب الدار
What is this?
ما هذا
Yu Xixi put the dummy here
وضعت المزيف هنا في منتصف الليل
and misled us.
‫لقد أساء فهمنا‬
We didn't find them.
لم نجده
Find them
‫احفر الأرض ثلاثة أقدام‬
at all events.
‫يجب العثور عليه أيضا‬
The forest is too big.
الغابة كبيرة جدا
We don't have enough people.
ليس لدينا ما يكفي من الرجال
I don't want any reason.
لا أريد سماع الأسباب
I want them.
أريد أن أرى شخصًا ما
Understood.
فهمت
Arrange it.
قم بالترتيب
We'll go back to Xianyun City tomorrow.
سنعود إلى مدينة شيان يون غداً
Xianyun City?
مدينة شيان يون
Yu Xixi is the daughter of Hai Liyuan.
"يو يي" هي ابنة "هاي لي"
Uncle San
‫هذا العم الثالث المتبقي
and Zang Muxiang
وعطر الخشب الأصلي
are from Yixiao Hall.
‫كلهم من نفس القسم‬
The Red Jade of Cangqiong
طالما
of the Laugh Master is not here,
إن اليشم الأحمر الذي يحمل الفارس الضحك ليس هنا
then where else could it be?
‫أين يمكن أن يكون‬
Yu Mansion?
‫قصر يو‬
There must be something we don't know.
‫بالتأكيد هناك شيء لا نعرفه‬
Don't tell anyone about this.
لا يجب أن تخبر الآخرين بهذا الأمر
Yes.
حاضر
It seems that my father didn't find
يبدو أن والدي لم يجد
Yu Zhao and Xixi.
لقد تم القبض عليهم
But Jin Gang was arrested.
لكن تم القبض على جين قانغ
I wonder
لا أعرف
how Zihe is now.
ماذا حدث الآن؟
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
Judging from how angry my father is,
‫انظر إلى غضب أبي
I guess they are fine.
أعتقد أنهم بخير
I hope so.
أتمنى ذلك
It's getting late.
لقد تأخر الوقت
Miss Liu, you shall rest early.
استريحي مبكرًا يا آنسة ليو
I really don't know
لا أعرف
why your father locked us up.
لماذا قام والدك بحبسنا معا
I know him
أبي
very well.
‫أنا أعرفه جيداً
After stabbing him,
إنه
he has stopped
منذ السيف السابق
seeing me as his son.
لم يعد يعاملني كأبنه
He only cares about
في قلبه
And I am
أما أنا
just a prisoner of his.
أنا مجرد سجين له
But what I'm worried about now
لكن ما يقلقني الآن هو
is that you might have become a prisoner of his.
ربما أصبحت سجيناً
From the beginning,
منذ البداية
my father probably didn't want you
قد لا يريدك أبي
to go back to Mirror Commander.
أن تعودي إلى جانب المرآة
Because in his eyes,
لأنه بالنسبة له
Mirror Commander was just a pawn.
‫المعلّم المرآة هو قطعة شطرنج‬
He could control him
السيطرة عليك
by controlling you.
هو السيطرة على الحارس المرآة
Well...
هذا
But don't worry, Miss Liu.
لا تقلقي يا آنسة ليو
I am always by your side.
أنا بجانبك
I will protect you.
سأحميك
Protect me?
حمايتي
Yes.
نعم
It's getting late.
لقد تأخر الوقت
Miss Liu, you shall rest early.
آنسة ليو، استريحي مبكرًا
I'll sit here.
سأجلس هنا
Come in. No one is inside.
ادخل لا يوجد أحد بالداخل
Brother, I checked. No one is here.
أخي لقد فحصت لا أحد
How did you know
كيف عرفت
they wouldn't wait for us in the cellar?
لن ينتظرونا في القبو
Ye Yunqing would never expect
يي يون تشينغ لم يتوقع أبدًا
we would come back.
أننا سنعود مرة أخرى
So it's safer here.
هذا المكان أكثر أماناً
I need to go out.
يجب أن أخرج
Get out?
‫اخرج‬
I need to go and save Jin Gang and Uncle San.
‫اذهب لإنقاذ جين قانغ و سان شو‬
Yu Zhao, are you crazy?
‫يوي تشاو  هل أنت مجنون‬
It's heavily guarded outside.
‫الآن هناك حراسة صارمة في الخارج‬
If you go out now, you can't save anyone.
إذا خرجت الآن لن يستطيع أحد إنقاذه
On the contrary, you'll put yourself in danger.
بل تضع نفسك في ورطة
I need to know
أريد أن أعرف أيضا
if they are still alive.
سواء كانوا على قيد الحياة أم لا
But...
‫لكن‬
I have something important to ask Uncle San.
‫لدي شيء مهم أريد أن أسأل العم الثالث‬
Why is there a secret chamber belonging to the Laugh Master here?
‫لماذا يوجد غرفة سرية شيا الضحك هنا‬
What does he have to do
الفارس الضاحك
with me being demonic when I was young?
‫ما علاقة ذلك‬
Probably only Uncle San knows the answers.
‫قد يعرف هذا فقط العم الثالث‬
Alright.
‫حسنا‬
I'll go with you.
سأذهب معك
Me too.
أنا أيضاً
No.
لا
It's more convenient for me to be alone.
‫سيكون من السهل أن أكون وحدي‬
This is
.حسنًا، حسنًا
a mechanical crossbow I made.
‫هو القوس الذي صنعته خصيصا‬
There are six arrows on it.
‫هناك ستة طلقات في الأعلى‬
Press here
إذا ضغطت على هذا المكان
and you'll shoot an arrow.
‫ستطلق القوس‬
Press this button
‫هذا الزر‬
and you'll shoot an arrow with a special chain.
‫ستطلق السهم الذي يحمل سلسلة حديدية خاصة‬
Press it again and it will be withdrawn.
‫إذا ضغطت مرة أخرى سترجع‬
It can help you escape.
يمكنه أن يأخذك إلى السماء
You must wear it.
يجب أن ترتديه جيدا
Huo, stay here and take care of them.
خوا، ابقي هنا واعتني بهم
Okay.
حسنا.
Let's check it.
‫لنذهب ونلقي نظرة
Uncle San.
‫العم الثالث
Young Master.
‫السيد الصغير
Why are you back?
لماذا عدت مرة أخرى؟
I'm here to get you out.
أنا هنا لإنقاذك
Leave now.
اذهب بسرعة
Look at my injury.
انظر إلى إصابتي
I can't leave.
لا يمكنني المغادرة
Jin Gang's injuries are worse than mine.
جين قانغ أصبت بشدة مني
If I hadn't hit his acupoints,
لو لم أشعل نقطة قوته
he wouldn't have survived.
لن يستطيع أن يتحمل ذلك
Leave now.
هيا بنا
Take Miss Xixi out of here.
‫أخرجوا الآنسة من هنا‬
What about you?
ماذا ستفعلين؟
Leave us alone.
لا تهتم بنا
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
We won't be in danger.
لن نقع في خطر
Ye Yunqing won't kill us.
يي يون تشينغ لن يقتلنا
He still needs us to threaten you.
لا يزال يريدنا أن نهددك
Leave now.
‫اذهب بسرعة‬
Uncle San.
‫العم الثالث‬
I have a question for you.
‫لدي سؤال لك
Young Master, please go ahead.
اسأل يا سيدي
What's your relationship
ما علاقتك
with the Laugh Master, Hai Liyuan?
ما العلاقة
You are the Vice Master of Yixiao Hall, Cheng Wen,
أنت السيد الثاني من طائفة يي شياو تشينج وين
and the sworn brother with the Laugh Master?
‫أنت والفارس الضاحك أخوان
Yes.
نعم
Bai Linglong is my wife.
باي لينغ لونغ هي زوجتي
In order to hide our identities,
‫من أجل إخفاء هويتها
she disguised herself as Zang Muxiang,
‫تحولت إلى شيانغ الخشب
and I used an assumed name of Uncle San.
‫تحولت إلى يو سان شو
I became her servant
‫من الزوجين‬
rather than her husband.
وأصبحوا خادمين
What about Yu Xixi?
ماذا عن ليلة البارحة؟
Yu Xixi
[ليلة البارحة]
is the daughter of the Laugh Master, Hai Liyuan.
هي ابنة الفارس الضاحك في البحر
Yu Xixi is the daughter of Hai Liyuan?
‫ليلة البارحة هي ابنة بحر‬
Yes.
نعم
Thirteen years ago,
ذلك قبل 13 عامًا
the Laugh Master saved you from the Golden Blade Sect.
أنقذك الفارس الضاحك من باب السيف الذهبي
That year, you were 12
عندما كنت في الثانية عشر من عمرك
while Xixi was 6.
‫في السادسة من عمرك
Have Cheng Wen and Bai Linglong arrived?
هل وصل زوجين تشينج وين و باي لينغ لونغ؟
They've been waiting in the lobby for a long time.
لقد انتظرنا في القاعة منذ وقت طويل
Take the kid in first.
خذ الطفل إلى الداخل
I'll be there soon.
سأصل بعد قليل
Yes.
نعم.
Who is this kid?
من هذا الطفل؟
He's badly injured.
أصيب بجروح خطيرة
His meridians are in disorder.
خطوط الطول فوضوية للغاية
Brother. Mrs. Hai.
أخي الأكبر، أختي بالقانون
Brother. Mrs. Cheng.
أخي الأصغر
I called you here tonight
‫دعوتكم إلى هنا الليلة‬
because I have a request.
من أجل طلب غير لائق
Just tell me.
أخبرني
This is Chief Feng Lie's eldest son,
هذا هو ابن فنغ ليه رئيس طائفة السيف الذهبي
Feng Zihe.
فينغ تسي خه
Something happened at the Golden Blade Sect tonight.
حدث شيء في طائفة السيف الذهبي الليلة
I saved Feng Zihe tonight.
أنقذت فينج زي خه طوال الليل
I want to leave him to you.
وأعتمد عليه إليكم
Leave...
‫توسل‬
Leave him to us?
كلفنا
I will also leave my daughter to you.
سأعتمد عليكم جميعا
Mr. Hai, what happened?
أخي، ماذا حدث؟
Ask no more.
لا تهتم
Take them to a place where no one knows them
خذهم إلى مكان لا يعرفهم أحد
and live a good life
إخفاء اسمهم
with a concealed identity.
أعيش حياة جيدة
I've sealed
لقد أغلقت نقطة الوخز
all their memories with point striking.
جميع ذكرياتهم
They won't remember what happened.
لن يتذكروا ما حدث
Don't let them enter the martial arts world again.
ولا تدعهم يدخلون عالم الكونغ فو
Please.
أرجوك
I discussed with Linglong.
سأتناقش مع لينغ لونغ
If our names should be changed,
بما أنها تخفي هويتك
we might as well
‫فمن الأفضل‬
alter all our identities completely.
تغيير كل الهوية
Linglong was good at medicine,
أنت ماهر في الطب
especially facial reshaping.
تجيد تغيير الوجه
So the two of us
لذلك نحن الاثنان
reshaped our faces
غيرنا الوجه
and settled down in Xianyun City.
.ويبقى في مدينة شيان يون
We built Huixian Restaurant
استخدم المال الذي أعطاه السيد هاي
with the money left by Brother Hai.
بناء مبنى هوي شيان
You know
‫ما حدث بعد ذلك
what happened later.
أنت تعرف كل شيء
Yixiao Hall was slaughtered
بسبب هذا الأمر
because of this?
تم قتل جميع أفراد عائلة يي شياو
I didn't know.
لا أعرف
The day after Yixiao Hall was slaughtered,
في اليوم التالي الذي تم قتله يي شياو
I went back to check secretly.
‫لقد عدت سرا للتحقق
All the corpses at the scene
جميع الجثث في الموقع
were from Yixiao Hall.
‫كلها من الضحك‬
Obviously,
من الواضح
someone tampered with them.
تم معالجته من قبل شخص ما
And the wounds of the bodies
كما أن جرح الجثة
were all caused by the Yanling Sword.
‫كلها بسبب يان لينغ داو
The Yanling Sword?
يان لينغ داو
Isn't that the sword used in the army?
أليس هذا السكين الذي يستخدمه الجيش؟
Yes.
نعم
So it was very strange.
لذلك هذا الأمر غريب للغاية
Looking back,
،وفكرت في ذلك اليوم
I thought Brother Hai
يبدو أن هاي
knew something.
يبدو أنه يعرف شيئاً
Uncle San.
‫العم الثالث
Did Hai Liyuan have anything to do with me being demonic?
‫هل هناك علاقة بيني وبين الهوية
What do you mean?
ماذا تعني؟
We found the secret room of Hai Liyuan.
لقد وجدنا غرفة سرية حدود البحر
There were some strange things written in it.
‫مكتوب فيه بعض الأشياء الغريبة‬
The secret room?
‫غرفة سرية‬
To be honest,
‫بصراحة‬
I didn't know there was a secret room
‫قبل اليوم‬
in the basement
‫لا أعرف أن هناك غرفة سرية‬
until today.
هناك غرفة سرية
I only knew that Brother Hai
أعلم فقط أن السيد هاي
came to this courtyard regularly
سيأتي إلى هذا الفناء
and locked himself in the room on the east all day long.
ويغلق نفسه في الغرفة الشرقية طوال اليوم
What about the the Red Jade of Cangqiong of Hai Liyuan?
ماذا عن اليشم الأحمر في البحر؟
Let's see if that old man is dead.
لنرى إن كان ذلك العجوز ميت أم لا
Young Master, you must leave now
سيدي، لنذهب
before it's too late.
‫إذا لم تغادر لن يكون هناك وقت
Hurry!
بسرعة
Young Master.
سيدي
Brother.
أخي
How are they?
كيف تسير الأمور
How are Uncle San and Jin Gang?
كيف حال العم الثالث و جين قانغ
They're all alive.
كلهم على قيد الحياة
Did you ask everything?
هل سألت بوضوح؟
I'm tired. Let's talk about it tomorrow.
أنا متعب، لنتحدث غداً
Okay.
حسنًا
Yu Xixi
[ليلة البارحة]
is the daughter the Laugh Master, Hai Liyuan.
هي ابنة الفارس الضاحك في البحر